

Benjamin ALLOUCH

IP/IT legal counsel, Data Protection Officer (DPO)

5 years post-qualification experience

WORK EXPERIENCES

2018 (1 year): Corporate Legal Counsel, Euris Health Cloud, Paris

- Data Protection, IT, Contract Law, Health Law
- > Health Data hosting and commercial contracts negotiation, redaction and validation (both In French and in English), general work about Data Protection regulation and Health Data Protection (GDPR, French Law...), trainee's supervisor
- > Acquired skills: working as the sole legal counsel of a SMB

2015 - 2017 (3 years): Legal Advisor, Cour de cassation (French Supreme Court, Research and Documentation Directorate), Paris

- ➤ <u>IP/IT Law, Civil Law</u>
- ➤ Whole study on IP/IT law at the Cour de cassation (legal researches, legal notices, involvement in meetings), participating in legal researches regarding various legal themes (teamwork with magistrates), supervision of a trainee, dealing with the appeals before the Court orientating them to the accurate legal chambers (this task requires a strong legal analysis)
- > Acquired skills: strong writing, analysis and report capacity, extensive legal researches

2013 – 2014 (10 months): In-House Legal Counsel, SNCF Legal Department, Paris

- > IP/IT Law, Contract Law
- Commercial contracts negotiation, redaction and validation (partnership, provision of service, purchase) and IT contracts mostly in English, legal advice regarding data privacy and trademark law, dispute management
- Acquired skills: strong expertise in contracts, redaction of legal notices, legislation regarding data privacy, reporting, managing emergency circumstances, autonomous and organized work, skillfulness tasks, and effort to adjust rapidly

2013 (5 months): Legal Intern, Technicolor, Paris

2012 (6 months): Legal Intern, SNCF Legal Department SNCF, Paris

Residence in Podgorica and Paris

⇒ Driving license LinkedIn

PROFILE

Sole legal counsel of a SMB for 1 year after 3 years at the French Supreme Court, I am specialized in IP/IT Law and currently envisaging a career change to become a freelance fullstack developer.

① + 382 69 206 234 / + 33 6 09 25 24 63

• 33, born in Montpellier (FRA)

<u> benjamin.allouch@gmail.com</u>

COMPETENCES

French **** English 🗮 *** Indonesian *** Spanish ___ **** Swedish **** **** React ****

INTERESTS

- ➤ Passionate about digital transition new issues, more particularly blockchain and cryptocurrencies (founder of French blog bitcoin-blockchain.fr), interested in IT and computing in general
- > Traveling the world: founder of French travel blog Visa Sans Détour, more than 40 countries visited, one year in Sweden (2009-2010) and several destinations each year
- ➤ Passionate about history of Byzantine and Ottoman Empires
- ➤ Significant sensitivity on environmental issues and promotion of renewable resources
- ► Sport: middle-distance runner (tournaments)

FORMATION

2019 - Present: Full-stack developer path, Openclassrooms (Europe *largest's online education platform)*

Coursework and projects: languages (HTML, CSS, JavaScript), building websites (WordPress, React, from scratch)

2012-2013: Master's Degree in IP/IT Law, *Université Paris 10 Nanterre*, (Cum Laude)

2010-2011: Master ("Maîtrise") in International Business Law, Université Paris 1 Panthéon-Sorbonne

2007-2010: Bachelor in Private Law (B)

➤ 3rd year **Erasmus**, Uppsala, Juridiska Fakulteten, Sweden (Teaching in English, Cum Laude)

➤ 1st and 2nd years: *Université Montpellier 1* (B)

2005-2008: Bachelor in History, Université Montpellier 3 Paul-Valéry